<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Renan F. Cunha</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Renan F. Cunha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:17:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debate with Sandbagging: A Minimal Extension of “More Persuasive LLM Debaters → More Truthful Answers”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sandbagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sandbagging/</guid>
      <description>One-line: Replicated the debate-improves-truth result; extended to N &amp;gt; 2 debaters with sandbagging roles. Judge accuracy improves with more debaters, but decreases when N − 1 debaters on the correct-answer team are sandbagging.&#xA;Why this matters Tests whether debate-style oversight can be subverted by strategic underperformance (sandbagging). Directly relevant to oversight-subversion benchmarks and collusion-style risks in automated regimes.&#xA;TL;DR Replication: Debating with More Persuasive LLMs Leads to More Truthful Answers. Extension: N-debaters + assigned sandbagger(s); measured effects on judge truth rate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIs doing 4-Hour Well-Defined Software Tasks by 2028</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai_software_2028_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 17:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai_software_2028_prediction/</guid>
      <description>See the METR analysis first1.&#xA;Based solely on that analysis, the most defensible near-term prediction is:&#xA;By 2028, AI systems will achieve 95–99% correctness on well-defined software tasks (≈ 4 human-hours) that can be auto-verified.&#xA;Why this target? METR specifically selected “automatically scoreable, relatively clean, greenfield software tasks” for their study. On these task, the effective task length (i.e., human-time equivalence) that AI systems can reliably solve has been growing exponentially, with a doubling time of ~7 months.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if Brazil were as good as Chile?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/brazil-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 14:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/brazil-chile/</guid>
      <description>GDP per capita would jump from $15,093 to $25,886 (1.71x). It would become the 4th largest economy globally, after the US, China, and India. Life expectancy would rise from 72.8 to 78.9 years (+6). The murder rate would drop from 22.38 to 3.63. Around 38,000 murders would be prevented annually. It could take between 7 and 14 years to get there, assuming a 4% to 8% yearly growth1. A long period, but at the same time, not that long2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Transhumanist Religion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/transhumanist-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 23:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/transhumanist-religion/</guid>
      <description>From Nick Bostrom&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Transhumanist FAQ&amp;rdquo;&#xA;While not a religion, transhumanism might serve a few of the same functions that people have traditionally sought in religion. It offers a sense of direction and purpose and suggests a vision that humans can achieve something greater than our present condition. Unlike most religious believers, however, transhumanists seek to make their dreams come true in this world, by relying not on supernatural powers or divine intervention but on rational thinking and empiricism, through continued scientific, technological, economic, and human development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examples of High State Capacity in Brazil</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/brazil-high-state-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 22:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/brazil-high-state-capacity/</guid>
      <description>Three examples of high state capacity in Brazil:&#xA;1. The COVID-19 Vaccine Rollout: Speed and Scale When faced with the monumental task of vaccinating its population against COVID-19, Brazil&amp;rsquo;s healthcare system rose to the challenge with impressive efficiency. Despite initial political hurdles to getting the vaccine, the rollout proceeded incredibly once it began.&#xA;Key factors in this success included:&#xA;Leveraging existing infrastructure: Brazil&amp;rsquo;s Universal Health System (SUS) provided a robust framework for vaccine distribution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Your Hero’s Journey?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hero-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 21:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hero-journey/</guid>
      <description>The Hero’s Journey, also known as the monomyth, is a narrative structure identified by mythologist Joseph Campbell. It describes a hero who embarks on an adventure, faces and overcomes a crisis, and returns transformed. This framework is ubiquitous, appearing in ancient myths, religious texts, and blockbusters like &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Star Wars.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The journey typically involves several key stages:&#xA;Protagonist: The hero of the story, is often an ordinary person. Shift: A significant change that sets the hero on their path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Efficient Market Hypothesis Lie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/efficient-market-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 01:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/efficient-market-lie/</guid>
      <description>The Efficient Market Hypothesis (EMH) states that all public (and maybe all private) information about an asset is already reflected in its price, making it impossible to consistently ‘beat the market’ since asset prices only react to new information.&#xA;If EMH is true, then it is impossible to predict stock prices, and you should probably be a passive investor (buying index funds). I used to believe that EMH was entirely accurate, but now I consider it a damn lie.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamming Questions of Your Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hamming-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:09:12 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hamming-life/</guid>
      <description>Richard Hamming was famous for asking, &amp;ldquo;Which are the most important problems in your field? Why are you not working on them?&amp;rdquo; Inspired by him, I tried to think about the most important problems in life. Here is my attempt:&#xA;Which career should you pursue? How hard should you work? Where should you live? Which friends should you surround yourself with? With whom should you share your life? How many kids, if any, should you have?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Personality Tests Better than Astrology?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/personality-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 21:38:52 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/personality-tests/</guid>
      <description>It seems so, at least for some things. A study explored whether some popular personality tests (a MBTI-inspired and the Big Five) could predict1 certain life outcomes, comparing these tests against astrology.&#xA;While, unsurprisingly, astrology performed no better than random chance, the personality tests had a weak but existing predictive power. The Big Five model was the best, explaining about 6% of the variance in various life outcomes, while the MBTI-inspired explained only 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Successful Hunter-Gatherer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/successfull-hunter-gatherer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 21:51:15 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/successfull-hunter-gatherer/</guid>
      <description>I recently watched the documentary &amp;ldquo;Hadza: Last of the First&amp;rdquo; which explores one of the few remaining hunter-gatherer tribes. After watching it, I wondered what makes someone &amp;ldquo;successful&amp;rdquo; in that environment. Humanity has spent most of its existence like that, so maybe we can draw valuable insights from this.&#xA;A successful male in this environment is a combination of being a good:&#xA;Hunter (provides for the community) Mentor (passes skills to younger generations) Mate (forms a long-term bond, raises a family) Leader (involves in community politics) To replicate that in modern society, you can:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Limit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/natural-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 19:59:40 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/natural-limit/</guid>
      <description>In bodybuilding, there is the concept of the &amp;ldquo;natural limit&amp;rdquo;. It means the maximum potential you can achieve without the use of steroids.&#xA;There are some interesting points about this concept:&#xA;Genetics matter and act as your limiting factor. Despite this, there is still significant room for improvement. For me, thinking in these terms has helped a lot; it releases some of the anxiety that I have when doubting whether I will be able to reach a goal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Bodybuilding?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-bodybuilding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 21:07:53 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-bodybuilding/</guid>
      <description>This is the physique evolution wants you to have:&#xA;The San hunther-gatherer tribe, residing in Southern Africa A physique with almost no fat and minimal muscle, given their limited food supply. Yet, this physique is exceptionally suited for prey chasing, making it ideal for hunting.&#xA;Now jump to the 21st-century. If you are a young male, with distinct genetics, willing to engage in rigorous training and stick to a very restricted diet, you can achieve a physique like this:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You are in Excellent Shape If You...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-in-excellent-shape-if/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 12:09:51 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-are-in-excellent-shape-if/</guid>
      <description>Have a body fat percentage of less than 10.5% Have a VO2 max of greater than 57.1 (or can run for 12 minutes at a pace of at least 14 km/h) Can complete a single rep of bench press with 1.32 times your body weight Can complete a single rep of leg press with 2.05 times your body weight Can do at least 36 push-ups Reference: ACSM normative data for 20-29-year-old males.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Tuesday</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/perfect-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 20:45:12 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/perfect-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>I tried to brainstorm the perfect Tuesday for myself, assuming I had no constraints. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I came up with:&#xA;Wake up naturally after a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep Take in morning sunlight while riding my bike (minimum of 6km) Have a healthy breakfast Engage in some &amp;ldquo;reflection&amp;rdquo; over a cup of coffee Think of three things I am grateful for Review my goals Review my habits Review my principles Review Anki flashcards Have a study/work session Do a weightlifting workout session with stretching at the end Have a healthy lunch Have another study/work session Have a healthy snack Enjoy some free time Have a healthy dinner Enjoy more free time Practice sleep hygiene What surprised me is how achievable this is, even with some constraints.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Exercise?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why_exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 20:43:48 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why_exercise/</guid>
      <description>to experience the pleasure of an euphoric state to improve your daily mood to improve your energy levels to enjoy the skill acquisition/challenge to postpone your death to enable yourself to participate in other cool activities, such as: hiking surfing rowing etc to age well, maintaining independence rather than becoming disabled to increase your attractiveness You likely find value in all or some of these benefits, which are difficult to obtain without regular exercise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge and Discipline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024_03_knowledge_discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024_03_knowledge_discipline/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you want to reach a goal, such as being able to do 40 push-ups when you currently can only do 5.&#xA;I believe there are mainly three things you need to reach your goal: natural capacity (absence of serious physical limitations, etc.), knowledge, and discipline. You cannot change the first factor, so let&amp;rsquo;s focus on the latter two.&#xA;Knowledge helps you figure out what you need to do. Imagine GPT-100 exists and is omniscient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving Contextual Bandits with Greediness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/greedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/greedy/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will explain and implement Epsilon-Greedy, a simple algorithm that solves the contextual bandits problem. Despite its simplicity, this algorithm performs considerably well [1].&#xA;Prerequisites A Very Short Intro to Contextual Bandits Python Numpy (Optional) Standard Multi-Armed Bandit Epsilon-Greedy Algorithm [2] Logistic Regression (You need to know what it is, not necessarily how it works) * Note: In this article, I use the words arm and action, and the words step and round, interchangeably.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brainstorming Benchmarks for Contextual Bandits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/benchmark/</guid>
      <description>Since contextual bandits are relatively new, they haven&amp;rsquo;t been studied and tested so heavily as standard multi-armed bandits algorithms [1]. This being the case, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to design benchmarks for contextual bandits so these algorithms can be reliably tested, compared and improved.&#xA;Prerequisites A Very Short Intro to Contextual Bandits Simplest benchmark Many people in the AI community recommend the use of toy problems, these low complexity examples provide better and faster debugging cycles, a good property of early-stage research and experimentation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Very Short Intro to Contextual Bandits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/contextual-bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/contextual-bandits/</guid>
      <description>In the contextual bandits problem, we have an environment with K possible actions. The environment returns some context x, taken from a distribution X. The environment also has a function f(x, k), that calculates the reward based on the context and the chosen action k.&#xA;The goal then is to find the policy $\pi$ that maximizes the rewards obtained in the long-term. A policy is a function that maps contexts to actions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
