<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Renan Cunha</title>
    <link>https://renan-cunha.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Renan Cunha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Your Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://renan-cunha.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Contextual Bandits with Greediness</title>
      <link>https://renan-cunha.github.io/posts/greedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renan-cunha.github.io/posts/greedy/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will explain and implement the epsilon-greedy algorithm, a simple algorithm that solves the contextual bandits problem. Despite its simplicity, this algorithm performs considerably well [1].
Prerequisites  A Very Short Intro to Contextual Bandits Python Numpy (Optional) Standard Multi-Armed Bandit Epsilon-Greedy Algorithm [2] Logistic Regression (You need to know what it is, not necessarily how it works)  * Note: In this article, I use the words arm and action, and the words step and round, interchangeably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainstorming Benchmarks for Contextual Bandits</title>
      <link>https://renan-cunha.github.io/posts/benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renan-cunha.github.io/posts/benchmark/</guid>
      <description>Since contextual bandits are relatively new, they haven&amp;rsquo;t been studied and tested so heavily as standard multi-armed bandits algorithms [1]. This being the case, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to design benchmarks for contextual bandits so these algorithms can be reliably tested, compared and improved.
Prerequisites  A Very Short Intro to Contextual Bandits  Simplest benchmark Many people in the AI community recommend the use of toy problems, these low complexity examples provide better and faster debugging cycles, a good property of early-stage research and experimentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Short Intro to Contextual Bandits</title>
      <link>https://renan-cunha.github.io/posts/contextual-bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renan-cunha.github.io/posts/contextual-bandits/</guid>
      <description>In the contextual bandits problem, we have an environment with K possible actions. The environment returns some context x, taken from a distribution X. The environment also has a function f(x, k), that calculates the reward based on the context and the chosen action k.
The goal then is to find the policy $\pi$ that maximizes the rewards obtained in the long-term. A policy is a function that maps contexts to actions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>